A Guide to the Film collection FA466
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John D. Rockefeller Jr., 10
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. 1921-1943, Silent and Sound, Black & white, 45 minutes (with time code). Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1365, Reel III 14.2-3, Reel AV 1365)
    - Compilation of JDR JR footage from China Medical Board Commission visit, European trips, and events in U.S.
    - CMBC visitors in Grand Central Station, NYC, 1921 August 11
    - CMBC visitors in Vancouver, B.C.
    - CMBC visitors onboard "The Empress of Asia", arriving at Yokohama, Japan
    - Governor-General of Chosen, Baron Saito, and wife, greet group
    - JDR JR greeted by Mayor Yoshimatsu of Keijo, Korea
    - sightseeing in Peking with members of the Chinese Bankers? Association
    - sightseeing in Pai Hai, the Forbidden City
    - dedication of Peking Union Medical College
    - NYC newsreel: "Rockefeller Center Seen as Center of World Unity" - cornerstone of British Empire Building.
    - Versailles, France newsreel: "JDR JR Honored by France" for restoration aid
    - NYC newsreel: "JDR JR Storms Center in Fight on Prohibition Repeal"
    - Washington D.C. newsreel "JDR JR Spurs Fingerprint Drive"; JDR JR fingerprinted, filed
    - NYC newsreel: "JDR JR Drives Last Rivet in the World's Greatest Building Project"
    - NYC newsreel: "Peace Has a Home" JDR JR founds the International House
    - Tarrytown NY newsreel: "JDR JR Restores America's Oldest Castle - Philipsburg Manor"
    - Providence, RI: JDR JR receives honorary doctorate from Brown University
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Family (1), 1917 April 3; Silent, Black & white, 9 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14 F 57, Reel AV 1733)
    Children; West Fifty-fourth Street (New York, N.Y.); Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979
    - 10 W. 54th St, NYC: children of JDR, JR. playing inside house; Laurance and Winthrop Rockefeller riding scooters inside; Laurance fixing scooter wheel.
  - JDR Jr. Family Home Movies, 1920s; Silent, Black & white, 8 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14 F 3, Box 1, Dvd AV 821, Reel AV 821, Dvd AV 3.47)
    Amateur films; Children; Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Historic buildings -- Conservation and restoration; Versailles (France); Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller family; Chateau de Versailles (Versailles, France)
    - shot of Family chauffeur fixing car on the side of the road
    - boxing matches aboard a ship
    - France: visit to Versailles, stone masons at work, cathedral restoration
    - Pocantico Hills, NY: Abeyton Lodge
    - Rockefeller family cookout, brothers making faces for camera
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Lincoln Day Speech, 1928; Sound only. 36 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1947)
    Audio of speech given on the occasion of Abraham Lincoln's birthday. JDR Jr speaks about the 18th Amendment, charity, and general guidelines for good behavior and morality: "Reputation is what people think we are, character is what we really are".
    Prohibition; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Ethics; Charity; Lincoln Day; Lincoln Day addresses; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
  - John D. Rockefeller Jr. Testifies at Oil Inquiry, 1933; Silent, Black & whie, 3 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14 F 24, Reel AV 73)
    Summary: newsreels from Congressional Inquiry to Standard Oil: 'Jackson, WY: "Throngs Wait for Glimpse of Famous Witness after Senate Teapot Probe". "JDR JR with Senator Gerald Nye", chairman of the committee investigating oil leases.
    Newsreels; Standard Oil Company; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
- Abby Rockefeller Mauze ("Babs"), 11
  - David Milton and McAlpin Families home movies, 1930s; Silent, Black & white, 10 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.3-6, Reel AV 1401, Reel AV 1400, Reel III 14.3-7)
    Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); John D. Rockefeller House (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Princeton (N.J.); Oyster Bay (N.Y.); Westbury (Nassau County, N.Y.); Amateur films; Golf; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Milton, D. M. (David Meriwether); Mauze, Abby Rockefeller
    - family in Princeton NJ, Oyster Bay NY, Westbury NY
    - with George and Margaret Strong de Cuevas (JDR's granddaughter) in Pocantico Hills.
    - Mitzi playing golf with her grandfather, JDR SR and uncle, DR, at Kykuit
  - David Milton Home Movies (3), 1930-1931, 1934; Silent, Black & white. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1348, Reel AV 1348, Reel III 14.3-11, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.3)
    Golf; Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Children; Swimming; Amateur films; Beekman Place (New York, N.Y.); Milton, D. M. (David Meriwether); Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison)
    - Pocantico Hills NY: daughter Mitzi swimming in pool, golfing with JDR Sr., 1930-1931
    - Beekman Place NYC: daughters Mitzi and Marilyn playing on roof., 1934 June
  - David Milton Family Home Movies (4), Silent, Black & white, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1349, Reel AV 1349, Reel III 14.3-5)
    Bicycles; Cycling; Seal Harbor (Me.); Amateur films; John D. Rockefeller House (Pocantico Hills, N.Y.); Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Milton, D. M. (David Meriwether)
    - Seal Harbor ME: at Milton House, 1931 Summer
    - Pocantico Hills NY
    - Visiting Kykuit, 1931 September
    - NAR and wife ride tandem bicycle
    - Babs poses with brothers and JDR Jr.
  - David Milton Family Home Movies (5), Silent, Black & white, 10 minutes. On;y available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1399, Reel III 14.3-12)
    Seal Harbor (Me.); Amateur films; Beekman Place (New York, N.Y.); Ormond Beach (Fla.); Milton, D. M. (David Meriwether); Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
    - Seal Harbor, ME: Mitzi sailing, Babs Rockefeller with children, David Rockefeller on beach, children playing at Seal Harbor Club, 1932 August
    - Ormond Beach, FL: Nelson Rockefeller, Laurance Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and friends on beach, 1933 January
    - Beekman Place, NYC: Mitzi (age 5) plays on roof of apartment; Mitzi and Marilyn (age 2) play at apartment., 1933 April
  - David Milton Family Home Movies (6), Silent, Black & white, 10 minutes. Some footage available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1384, Reel AV 1407, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.3, Reel III 14.3-12)
    Beekman Place (New York, N.Y.); Fishing; Amateur films; Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Swimming; Milton, D. M. (David Meriwether)
    - Beekman Place, NYC: Mitzi doing acrobatics; Mitzi and Marilyn playing, 1934 June
    - Pocantico Hills NY: Marilyn and Mitzi playing at the Milton house, riding go-cart, swimming in pool, fishing, playing with dogs; daughters at beach, on farm, on raft.
  - Looney Tunes by Babs (David Milton home movies), 1930-1935; Silent, Black & white, 17 minutes. Some footage available on DVD. (Box 2, Dvd AV 1352, Reel AV 1352, Reel III 14.3-1)
    compilation of home movies 1930-1935, shot by Babs and Abby Rockefeller, edited by Babs and Mitzi at later date.
    Beekman Place (New York, N.Y.); Sutton Island (Me.); Ormond Beach (Fla.); Amateur films; Golf; Seal Harbor (Me.); Pocantico Hills (Sleepy Hollow, N.Y.); Swimming; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison); Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich; Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, David; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Milton, D. M. (David Meriwether); Rockefeller family; Rockefeller, Mary (Mary Todhunter Clark); Mauze, Abby Rockefeller
    - Pocantico Hills NY
      - Mitzi swimming in pool, playing in garden, golfing with JDR SR, sitting in pony cart.
      - JDR SR in car.
      - DR and Mitzi in sheep barn, playing near Japanese kale
      - Mitzi on horse (?Rastus?) with riding master Joe Plick.
      - family cars
      - JDR 3rd playing croquet with Laurance and Winthrop Rockefeller and David Milton
      - 5 Rockefeller brothers posed on Abeyton Lodge porch with Babs and Mitzi
      - Nelson Rockefeller and wife Mary Todd on tandem bicycles.
    - Seal Harbor, ME: Abby, Mitzi, Marilyn & David Milton sailing, playing at Sutton Island., 1932 August
    - Ormond Beach, FL: Nelson Rockefeller with wife Mary Todd, Babs, Laurance and David Rockefeller, and David Milton on beach
    - Beekman Place, NYC: Mitzi and Marilyn playing on roof, 1934 June
  - Opening of Greenacre Park, New York City, 1971 October 14; Sound, Color, 1 minute. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1606, Reel III 14.9-3)
    NBC news excerpt about park, funded by Abby Mauze; opening ceremony attended by JDR 3rd, Nelson, Laurance, Winthrop, and David Rockefeller
    Greenacre Park (New York, N.Y.); NBC News; Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich); Rockefeller, John D.; Rockefeller, Winthrop; Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman; Rockefeller, David
  - Rockefeller Family Films Reel 5, 1930s; Silent, Color, 12 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1007)
    unedited footage of Babs Rockefeller and her family on vacation in Europe: daughters riding horses, sightseeing in France and Amsterdam, a military parade in Paris in La Place de la Concorde, posing with Mary Todd Rockefeller and family, and scenes of Clydesdale horses.
    Europe; Family vacation; Vacations; Amsterdam (Netherlands); Horse riding; France; Mauze, Abby Rockefeller; Rockefeller, Mary (Mary Todhunter Clark)
- John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 12
  - Episode of NewsFront: Segment with John D. Rockefeller, 1967 December 16 (Reel III 14.1 Ff 49)
  - Asian Art Collection, 1970; Silent, Color, 4 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1113)
    Footage from the opening of the JDR 3rd Asian Art Collection at the Asia Society. JDR 3rd and wife Blanchette are in attendance.
  - Bicentennial: Beyond the Birthday, 1975; Sound, Color, 28 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1945)
    Film about the projects and ideas generated around the Bicentennial. Introduced by President Ford, the film features interviews with prominent figures and examines civic projects all looking to examine the history of the US so far, and to make constructive plans for the future. Interviews with JDR 3rd, Ladybird Johnson, Dr. Jonas Salk, and others.
  - Frontiers of Faith, 1952; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1713, Reel III 14.4-10)
    NBC presentation: panel discussion about Christian ministry and religion in America with JDR 3rd (as president of the RBF, the RBF Fund for Theological Education began in 1952); panel includes Eugene Carson Blake (moderator), Liston Pope, Ralph Sockman, Nathan Pusey.
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1952; Sound, Color, 12 minutes, only available on original 35mm film. (Reel AV 1108, Reel III 14.4-9)
    Compilation of newsreel footage from 1952: King and Queen of Jordan visit to Madrid; JDR 3rd gives speech in Japan & visits International Culture Center; viewing British helicopters in England.
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd: Population Explosion, 1967; Sound, Color, 1 minute. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1652, Reel III 14.4-15)
    From an ABC interview, a short statement from JDR 3rd on the realities of family planning in response to the question, "What is the scope of the problem of the population explosion?"
  - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Lecture, 1973 October 31; Sound, Color, 45 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1864, Reel III 14 F60)
    Speech by JDR 3rd about the U.S. Bicentennial (1976), the current state of the nation, and remembering his recently deceased brother, Winthrop. Introduced by his nephew, Winthrop P. Rockefeller, who pays tribute to his father and the Rockefeller Family. Filmed at the University of Arizona six months after the death of Winthrop A. Rockefeller.
  - JDR IV Campaign in West Virginia, 1966; Sound and silent, Color, 34 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 110, Box 1, Dvd 110, Reel III 14 F2)
    Report on JDR IV campaign for West Virginia seat in House of Delegates, reported by Paul Duke of NBC.
  - Kaleidoscope Interview with JDR 3rd, 1969 April 30; Sound, Black & white, 28 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.4-11, Box 2, Dvd AV 1390, Dvd AV 1325, Reel AV 1325)
    JDR 3rd interviewed by James Day about the realities and responsibilities of being a Rockefeller. Questions: Was there a spirit of competition between the brothers? Were you groomed for philanthropic responsibility? What pursuit has given you the most satisfaction? What is your rationale for giving?
  - Lincoln Center Opening, 1963; Sound, Black & white, 3 minutes. Only available on original 35mm film. (Reel III 14.5-12, Reel AV 1704)
    Lincoln Center NY: construction; opening of first units; views of interior; visits with JDR 3rd, Nelson Rockefeller, Jacob Javits, Jacqueline Kennedy.
  - National Conference on Citizenship, 1970; Sound, Black & white, 45 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14 F1, Reel AV 109)
    Coverage of bipartisan workshop on student involvement with the electoral process, informal panel discussions-film funded with grants from the Stern Foundation and JDR 3rd.
  - Pilgrimage to Virginia, 1946 March 8; Silent, Black & white and color, 9 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1117)
    Winston Churchill visits Virginia with his wife and daughter: speech at the Virginia General Assembly in Richmond with General Eisenhower and Governor William Tuck; visit to Colonial Williamsburg with JDR 3rd, Kenneth Chorley, and General Eisenhower.
  - Population and the American Future, Part I, 1972; Sound, Color, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.4-2, Reel AV 1712, Reel AV 1711)
    Overview of findings from 2-year research project on population growth funded by JDR III, Ford Foundation, Commonwealth Fund, Xerox Corp, and the Scaife Family Fund. Part I: change in life expectancy, population growth statistics, environmental deterioration, national security, illegal immigration, urban development, national distribution policy.
  - Ramon Magsaysay Award Foundation, 1958; Sound, Black & white, 5 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1017)
    Compilation of news footage: reporting on US funding of agriculture projects in the Philippines, then coverage of first Ramon Magsaysay Foundation award, with President Garcias and JDR 3rd.
  - The Today Show: Performing Arts in America, 1965 March 9; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1654, Reel III 14.4-14)
    A study of the performing arts in America, supported by JDR 3rd. The study stresses that the arts should have the same public funding and accessibility as museums or libraries, and the importance of bringing professional standards and quality to community and school-level programs. Barbara Walters and Hugh Downs are the interviewers.
  - United Nations Population Explosion, 1967; Sound, Color, 11 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1653, Reel III 14.4-13)
    Film on ABC about family planning in New York City, with sound bites from JDR 3rd and various international public leaders. Relates to article written by JDR 3rd "The Greatest Challenge" in Reader's Digest (1966 October).
  - Urban Gateways: Art Safaris, Sound, Color, 27 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 873, Reel IV 3B 10.11 Fe1)
    Film from theater group funded by the JDR 3rd Fund
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Personal, 13
  A group of amateur and professional films, television episodes, etc., belonging to or featuring NAR. Films relating to NAR’s political career are listed separately.
  - The Art of Collecting, Sound, Color, 40 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1072, Reel III 14.1 Fg 59)
    NBC documentary on wealthy figures and their various collections (includes interview with Nelson Rockefeller in the Executive Mansion in Albany)
  - Cancer Cures, Sound, Color, 25 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1838, Reel III 14.1 Ff 85)
    Segment from CBS 60 Minutes.
  - First Baby Atom Blast, 1955 February 18; Black & white, 1 minute. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1188, Reel III 14.1 Fa 35)
    Footage of a nuclear test explosion.
  - Jackie O at Opening of New York City Cultural Center, 1963; Sound, Black & white, 4 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1704, Reel III 14.5-12)
    Footage from 1963 opening of the first section of Lincoln Center. JDR 3rd enters building with Jacqueline Kennedy with other dignitaries; some scenes from the inside; construction footage.
  - Maragoli: A Population Study, Sound, Color, 50 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 58, Reel AV 1932)
    Documentary on overpopulation in Western Kenya
  - NASA Astronaut Film, event date: 1969 January 10; Sound, Color, 5 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1254, Reel III 14.1 Fa 103)
    Film of Apollo VIII mission, narrated by Art Fleming, which was shown at a New York State dinner for the Apollo VIII astronauts and their wives (1969 January 10)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Dartmouth Reunion I, 1935; Silent, Black & white, 8 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.5-6, Reel AV 1410)
    1935 footage from Class of 1930 reunion in Hanover VT: classmates join baseball game on campus, marching band, picnic on the Haffenraffer Estate, etc.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller: Dartmouth Reunion II, Silent, Black & white, 8 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.5-7, Reel AV 1409)
    Hanover, VT: Senior class officers, Alpha Delta Phi fraternity baseball game, Beth Theta Pi group in front of house, Psi Upsilon baseball game, Sigma Alpha Epsilon play cards; views of Dartmouth campus; hazing scene with men dressed liked babies in competition for "cutest baby".
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Dartmouth Reunion III, Silent, Black & white, 8 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.5-8, Reel AV 1408)
    Hanover, VT: group shots of classmates with wives, classic car scenes, swimming and baseball.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family Film II, 1940s; Silent, color, 9 minutes, Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.5-3, Reel AV 1068)
    1940s footage of Nelson Rockefeller family on vacations: Yellowstone Park WY at Old Faithful, at Jackson Lake Lodge, riding horses; playing at Seal Harbor, twins on the beach; Pocantico Hills-Hawes House, visiting with JDR JR and Abby, sailing boats.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family III, 1950; Silent, Color, 11 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.5-4, Box 2, Dvd AV 1069, Reel AV 1069)
    1950 footage of the family playing at Pocantico Hills with JDR JR: playing in pool, eating on patio; additional footage from the graduation of Steven Rockefeller from Princeton University.
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller Family IV, 1930s-1940s; Silent, Black & white, color, 11 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.5-5, Box 2, Dvd AV 1070, Reel AV 1070)
    - 1930s and 1940s travelogues from Asia and the western United States
    - NAR and MTR in the Far East, Chinese boats, rice paddies
    - Pocantico Hills: Mary Todd Rockefeller and children playing in garden
    - miscellaneous footage from trip through the American West
    - Seal Harbor: Mary Todd Rockefeller and children on the beach
  - Reagan Speech at Disneyland Hotel, 1973 September 12; Sound, Color, 35 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fg 54, Reel AV 1927A, Reel AV 1927B)
    Ronald Reagan address to the California Bar Association, at the Disneyland Hotel.
  - Rodman Rockefeller on Newsfront, 1968 May 18; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel III 14.11-1, Box 2, Dvd AV 1100, Reel AV 1100)
    New York City NY: interview about history of the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC).
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, Political Career, 14
  Footage from campaigns, conventions, and official events that are specifically related to political activities in the life of NAR. Many dozens of campaign commercials, including TV and radio spots.
  Chronological.
  - Undated
    - WNBF-TV Interview with NAR, pre 1958; Sound, Black & white, 2 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1258, Reel III 14.1 Fa 107)
      Interview with Nelson Rockefeller about George Hindman and the State Constitutional Commission (filmed pre-1958).
    - Homenaje a los Alcaldes de Puerto Rico, Sound, Color, 8 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1116)
      produced by the Miller Brewing Company, footage of awards dinner with Governor Nelson Rockefeller and other speakers, featuring Miller High Life beers as sponsor. Also has footage of the Puerto Rico Day Parade in Manhattan.
  - 1945
    - United Nations Conference with U.S. Delegates 1945, Sound, Black & white, 3 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1656, Reel III 14.1 Fb 55, Box 1, Dvd AV 1656)
      Nelson Rockefeller is shown at beginning of international conference
    - Pan-American Day, 1945 April 14; Sound, Black & white, 12 minutes. Only available on original 35mm film. (Reel AV 1618, Reel III 14.5-13)
      Presentation of a proclamation from Connecticut Governor Raymond B. Baldwin to Secretary of State Nelson Rockefeller.
  - 1958
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Shots from Fox News, 1958; Sound, Black & white, 26 minutes. Available on DVD. (Reel AV 1700, Box 1, Dvd AV 3.38, Reel III 14.5-10)
      A newsreel compilation from 1958.
      - New York City NY: reception for NAR during his gubernatorial campaign
      - Dwight D. Eisenhower arriving in NYC.
      - Nelson Rockefeller and Dwight D. Eisenhower in 5th Avenue parade.
      - JDR 3rd with Senator Keating
      - Construction of the Interfaith Center.
      - NAR family portrait
      - President Eisenhower with Nelson Rockefeller.
      - Rockefeller and David Kennedy
      - Glen Falls NY: Nelson Rockefeller campaigning
      - Venezuela: NAR and wife on visit
      - Albany, NY: Nelson Rockefeller swearing-in ceremony and celebration; Mrs. NAR sewing union labels on clothing.
    - Dewey Endorsement of Republican Candidates, 1958; Silent, Black & white, 16 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel AV 1544, Reel III 14.1 Fd 5)
      1958 campaign, Thomas Dewey's endorsements of candidates Nelson Rockefeller, Wilson, Keating, and Lefkowitz, shot by CBS.
    - Kenneth Keating, 1958; Sound, Black & white, 14 minutes. Only available on orignal 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 4, Reel AV 1558)
      1958 Campaign: footage of President Eisenhower and Senator Javits visiting with candidate Keating.
    - Rockefeller on the Issues: Speaking From the Desk, 1958; Sound, Black & white, 25 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 1, Reel AV 1543)
      episode 12 of a series of broadcast speeches during the 1958 campaign, produced by the NYS Republican Committee.
    - NAR on Face the Nation, 1958 January 12; Sound, Black & white, 30 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fe 69, Reel AV 1073)
    - NAR on the Issues of Organized Labor, 1958 October 20; Sound, Black & white, 14 minutes. Only available on orignal 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 2, Reel AV 1530)
      Remarks of Governor Rockefeller from the New York Republican state Committee Meeting
    - Senator Javits Speech, 1958 October 20; Sound, Black & white, 15 minutes. Only available on original 16mm film. (Reel III 14.1 Fd 3, Reel AV 1559)